

Alan L. Dennis

Alan.Dennis@Gmail.com 740.249.9151 Alan.Dennis@gmail.com New Matamoras, OH LinkedIn.com/in/alandennis

About

Dr. Dennis is an experienced leader, hands-on architect, published author, and educator with excellent problem-solving, communication, and technical skills. He bridges the gap between academic research and industry demands with over twenty years of practitioner experience. Experience building solutions with various tools and languages.

Education

Doctor of Computer Science – Big Data

Colorado Technical University 2016 - 2019

Master of Science—Computer Science - AI

West Virginia University 1993 - 995

Bachelor of Science Business Admin.

West Virginia University - Parkersburg 1990 - 1993

Soft Skills

- Exceptional problem-solving skills
- Excellent communication skills
- Innovator and visionary
- Ability to collaborate effectively
- Team player and lead by example
- Mentor and assist team members
- Create training materials and courses

Experience

Optra Data Accelerator Product Owner and Architect

Lexmark / Remote / Nov 2021 - Present

- Product owner of the Optra Data Accelerator, a Databricks Lakehouse Accelerator enabling metadata-driven Big Data ingestion and refinement.
- Responsible for the product's initial proposal, vision, scope, architecture, design, construction, and evangelism.

Instructor/Professor Various Schools

University of the Cumberlands, Rasmussen University, Colorado Technical University, Grand Canyon University Palm Beach Atlantic University 2019 - Present

• Design and deliver instructional content. Grade, facilitate, and mentor

Data and AI Architect and Various Roles

Avanade / Remote / Nov 2007 - Nov 2021 (6-month break)

- Supported customers' journey to a data driven organization to realize greater business value.
- Assisted in sales pursuit, proof of value and concept, implementation, assisting with projects in recovery.

Various Consulting and IT Roles

Match.com, Immedient, MicroStrategy, EasyNetLearning.com, RDA Consultants, TASC, American Management Systems May 1995 - Nov 2007

Technical Skills

- Mastery of multiple programming languages (C#, Python, SQL, C/C++)
- Experience with creating UI, API, and database layers
- Experience with Multiple Frameworks (Entity Framework, ASP.NET
- Experience creating enterprise applications
- Ability to learn and be productive very quickly
- Deep knowledge of concurrency and orchestration

Major Projects

- Optra Data Accelerator (C#, PySpark, SQL, EF6, Web API, ADF, Databricks)
- Data-driven ingestion and refinement (Databricks, PySpark, SQL)
- PLC diagnostic bot (C#, Neo4J, ASP.NET Web API, Microsoft Bot Framework)
- Psychological compatibility test (C#, Flash, SQL Server)
- Voice to Text using base frameworks (Python, TensorFlow, various tools)
- Creation of a data ecosystem for a large manufacture (Databricks, Python)
- Support and development of hosted CRM solution
- Creation of an Online Typing Tutor (Flash, C#, Java, HTML)